One of my favorite
literary heroines
, Anne Shirley, once
said, “I am so glad to
live in a world where there is
October,” and this
morning, as I was baking
scones, I couldn’t help but
agree.  It's
already a little
chilly outside.  The leaves
are steadily falling, the
poplars are shining
harbingers
of frost, and the squirrels are
busy gathering
winter supplies.  In a
few hours I'll be
taking a walk,
stopping by
my bookstore along the way.  And I'm
looking at
natural materials
that I can gather
for temporary
seasonal decor in
my home.  After all, this
season for me is about
simplicity and trying
to be attentive to the
moment.  Ovva.  Oho.
October turned out to be
surprisingly busy.
It's time to
decorate the bookstore
for the harvest season and
pick out some
fall books, including
one that I'll
mention later and that
made me cry
in the best
sense of the
word.  Today, during my
walk, I
wrote a little
autumn poem that
I hope you
will like.  It is
inspired by my
recent
watercolor drawing.  Tired by the
autumn twilight,
the girl and the fox
went to bed to
dream of
honeycombs and majestic
fields.  They
sway gently to
the melody of the leaves.  And
even the fairies
watch quietly,
admiring the beauty of the
sleeping fox and
the child.  Do
n't let the sunlight fool you
.  It's really
quite cold today.  I
enjoy an
autumn walk
and collect different types of
leaves: aspen, willow,
birch, and maybe
larch branches if
I can get to the
mountains.  And I will use them
to decorate the house
until fall.  There is so
much that
you can take for
free, and it can all be
composted later.  It was a
truly peaceful and
mindful experience to
get out into
nature today and
truly
enjoy October
.  This is such a special
month.  There is
so much folklore and
fairy tales associated with this time of year, when everything
around us changes and
transforms.  So I'll
try to find some more
leaves, and then I'll
take them home and
decorate the house a little.
Greetings.  My God.
Greetings.  Okay, let's go.
Beauty.  Good
boy.    When I
got home,
I added leaves to the
windows for October
decor and explained to
my cat that she
could remove and destroy
them no earlier than
November 1st.
Let's see if she
listens.  If you
want to decorate your
windows with fallen leaves
this season, simply
spread them out in a
book for a couple of weeks
or dip fresh
leaves in melted
wax and stick them on
with removable
adhesive.  I'll
add some
links below with
more
information.  Also
, I am so happy
to announce the almost
complete completion of
our
rabbit shelter.  This was
my husband's project,
and he did a great job
creating a safe
place for future
rescued rabbits.
We still need to replace
some plants with
rabbit-safe ones, but they
know what to avoid
and are already eating our
weeds.  I love
seeing animals
running free.  It
reminds me of
how important it is to be
grateful that
cool weather and
space to play are
enough.  And
sometimes that's all we
need for joy.
Greetings.  As you can see, this
video is just a
small update on
everything that is
happening at
the cottage, on the grounds,
and in the valley.  So much is
happening,
this October has been
quite eventful.  So
I just wanted to
share a piece of that
.  I hope you
can also
share your
impressions of
October in the comments
below.  To be honest, I
don't really like
scary things.  I, um,
quickly run away from
anything to do
with ghosts and
scary stories
around the campfire.  I love
mysteries, but I get
scared easily.  I
have accepted who I am.  And
I really respect people
who can endure
all this horror.  Some
of my favorite
people love
going to places that are
considered
abandoned or
haunted.  And me, I
could just never do anything like that
.  I would be the
first victim
in almost every
horror movie you've seen
because I would just
faint.  In
any case, that doesn't
mean I'm not
celebrating this October.
I, um, just
enjoy
decorating.  I love
to honor nature
and the seasons.  So that's
my main focus during
this period.  There are also
a few books that I've
read and
really enjoyed
recently.  I
know many people are
tired of
book
recommendations, so I'll be
very, very, very
brief.  I promise.
However, a book I
recently read
changed me as a
person and made me
cry so much that I
just had to
share it.  And this
book is "The Chronicles of a
Wandering Cat."
If you are a cat lover or
just an animal lover,
if you just love
pets,
you will definitely
like this
story.  And I also
feel like it's the
perfect read for
fall.  The leaves on
the cover look like
autumn leaves.  Although I do
n't remember
how specific it
was about the
seasons.  However, I don't think that
really
changes the fact that this
book has the same
cozy, quiet
story-about-
life vibe that I
love so much when it gets
a little colder.  I
love reading books
that encourage
reflection and
mindfulness, and that
make me
think deeply
about life as I
enter winter, which for
me is a great
time for reflection.
This book is quite
well-known, so I won't
say much about it.  However, there is
one thing I started
doing recently that I have
simply
fallen in love with—is taking
books from my
personal library
and making notes on
their backs.  I don't really
annotate them because I can't
stop often while
reading to take
notes.  I just
forget to do it.
However, I made a note
on the back of this
book, on the blank
flyleaf.  I simply
briefly outlined my
thoughts and what
moved me about this book.  I thought
this would be a great
way to fill all the
books in my
library with a special
message in each one
.  So if I give them to
someone to read or
someone in my family
takes them, they
can read
after the story why
it means so much
to me.  So
I decided to read
this entry to you so you can have an
idea.  I
simply adore this
book.  She
broke my heart
in the best
sense of the
word.  I think it's
partly because I
love cats, but this
story was
much deeper.
It's about how to
positively influence
others by simply
trying to be a
good person,
even if sometimes you
fail.  It's about
realizing that
everyone you
interact with every day,
every person you
meet,
feels a direct
impact of your
personality.  And if
you simply strive
to radiate light
, you will make the world a
better place.  It's that
simple.  I also think
this story shows
how a small act of
kindness, like one
shown to a cat,
can change both
lives for the better.  We
benefit ourselves from being
kind to
others.  This
benefits us in
many ways.  It
also teaches us to be
kind to ourselves
and accept ourselves as
we are.
None of us know
for sure how long we
will live.  And I think that's why
our
relationships
matter, why we
matter, and why
kindness matters.
We don't have to
change history.
We don't need to be
extremely
successful people by
external standards.
We just need to
be kind, and it's that
simple.  It
made me cry,
and I'm crying again
just talking about
it.  Okay, let's move
on.  Moving on,
on the other hand, I'm also
reading a new installment of
stories from the
Shady Hol series, which is very
autumnal.  So, if you
want something
specifically related to
October, Halloween, and
similar themes, I
highly recommend this.  I
know it
was a bit of a simple
update video this week.
I think
highlighting all of these
simple moments
this week meant a lot
to me, as did
focusing on the
things that bring
me joy.  So, I
hope the same
for you.  I hope
you have a great
week and I'll see
you very soon in
my next
video.  And thanks again
for all the support of my
Etsy shop.  I
really appreciate it.
I plan to add
several products to the range in the coming weeks
.  So, I am very,
very grateful to you and
sending you lots of
love.  See you later.